



# Timé Kadel

## **Engineer in IT & Electronics**

#### **Get In Touch**

https://timekadel.com



contact@timekadel.com



### ABOUT ME

I am a 28 years old engineer in Electronics and information technology from France who enjoys working on a various range of innovative technologies and projects. Fueled by a passion for researching and developing innovative and open source solutions, I have worked on creating my own company during the past few years.

## **SKILLS**

#### WEB - VUE.JS | NODE.JS | MYSQL | WEBGL

Specification, design, development and documentation of open source librairies and frameworks. Full stack development, test and deployment of complex WEB applications. Creative coding of dynamic 3D scenes for the WEB.

EMBEDDED SYSTEMS - PCB DESIGN (Altium, Kicad, Proteus) | C/C++ | FREERTOS Multilayer printed-circuit board design. Embedded software programming on ARM Cortex-M4 targets. High and low level peripheral drivers programming. Technical specification and system documentation.

PROFESSIONAL - AUTONOMY | ORGANISATION | TEAMWORKING | CREATIVITY Creativity structuring through agile project management using the Kanban method and creative problem solving. Teamwork management through clear task distribution and collaborative work goals formulation.

## **EXPERIENCE**

FOUNDER & CTO - AUTONOMOUS STAGE LIGHTING SYSTEMS | FR | 2019 - 2022 Setting new industry standards by researching and developing innovative solutions for show control. Business planning, market analysis and case study on intellectual property rights. Specification, design and documentation of software and hardware solutions.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER - WEARABLE TECHNOLOGIES LTD. | UK | 2016 - 2018 Helped closing last funding round by specifying, designing and developing an IoT platform dedicated to monitoring worker's smart garment's sensors activity in order to reduce health and environmental risks from hazardous sites.

PYROTECHNICIAN - STARDUST PYROTECHNIE, FÉÉRIE | FR, UK | 2012 - 2022 Licensed Professional pyrotechnician (C4T2N2). Programming, installation and firing of over 50 pyromusical shows across France and England. Management of experienced pyrotechnician teams.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **ENGINEERING IN ELECTRONICS & IT | 2019**

ESEO - Angers - France

#### HND IN ELECTRONICS & IT | 2014

IUT de Nantes - Nantes - France

#### BAC STI GÉNIE ÉLECTRONIQUE | 2010

Lycée Livet - Nantes - France

Native

Fluent - C2

Inermediate - Al





# Timé Kadel

# Ingénieur Logiciel & Hardware

#### **Me Contacter**

https://timekadel.com



contact@timekadel.com



## A PROPOS

Ingénieur de 28 ans en électronique et informatique industrielle, j'apprécie particulièrement d'investir mes compétences au profit de projets innovants. Artificier professionnel, j'ai consacré ces dernières années à un projet entrepreneurial visant à lier mes compétences d'ingénieur au domaine du spectacle son et lumière en y proposant des solutions logicielles et matérielles innovantes.

## COMPÉTENCES

### WEB - VUE.JS | NODE.JS | MYSQL | WEBGL

Spécification, design, création et documentation de librairies et frameworks open source. Développement full stack, test et mise en production d'applications WEB. Programmation créative de scènes 3D dynamiques pour le WEB.

## EMBARQUÉ - CONCEPTION PCB | C/C++ | FREERTOS

Conception de circuits imprimés multi-couches. Développement de logiciels embarqués sur cibles d'architecture ARM Cortex-M4. Conception de pilotes de périphériques bas et haut niveau. spécification et documentation de systèmes.

## PROFESSIONNEL - TRAVAIL EN ÉQUIPE | CRÉATIVITÉ | ORGANISATION | AUTONOMIE Création et gestion de projets en autonomie. Mise en pratique de méthodes agiles au travers du système kanban. Management d'équipes de pyrotechniciens.

## **EXPÉRIENCE**

## CRÉATEUR & CTO - AUTONOMOUS STAGE LIGHTING SYSTEMS | FR | 2019 - 2022

Projet de création d'entreprise spécialisée dans la recherche et le développement de solutions innovantes dédiées à l'automatisation du spectacle son et lumière. Réalisation d'un business plan et étude de cas sur la propriété intellectuelle. Spécification, design et documentation de solutions logicielles et matérielles.

## DEVELOPPEUR WEB FULL STACK - WEARABLE TECHNOLOGIES | UK | 2017 - 2018 Conception, spécification, design et création d'une plateforme IoT dédiée à surveiller l'activité de capteurs placés sur des équipements de protection individuelle dans le but de réduire les risques d'accidents dans les chantiers.

## PYROTECHNICIEN - STARDUST PYROTECHNIE, FÉÉRIE | FR, UK | 2012 - 2022 Artificier professionnel agréé C4T2N2. Programmation, câblage, sécurisation et mise à feu de plus de 50 installations pyrotechniques à travers la France et l'Angleterre. Chef d'équipes de pyrotechniciens amateurs et confirmés.

## **FORMATIONS**

#### INGÉNIEUR GÉNÉRALISTE OPTION IOT | 2019

ESEO - Angers - France

### **DUT GEII OPTION ÉLECTRONIQUE | 2014**

IUT de Nantes - Nantes - France

## BAC STI GÉNIE ÉLECTRONIQUE | 2010

Lycée Livet - Nantes - France

Langue Maternelle

Bilingue - C2 - TOEIC 930

Débutant - A2